准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
铅笔狼人诅咒
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
那是个适合埋头苦读的黑夜
It was a dark and studious night
谢谢你帮我突击明天的驾考
Thanks for helping me cram for my driver's exam
第307题
Question 307:
二十点转向要打哪个档位
What gear should you use
when making a twenty-point turn?
我想想
Let's see
二十点除以档位x
Twenty points divided by X number of gears
乘以半钢子午线轮胎半径
times the radius of a steel belted tire
被纸划到了
Paper cut
好漂亮
Pretty
黑夜中有一傻瓜
If a fool in the dark of night
借着惨白的月光涂鸦
should doodle by the moon's pale light
就会化为铅笔狼人  对吧
a WereDoodle they shall become, alright?
第二天早上
昨晚肯定是学得太拼了
That must've been one wild night of studying
我什么东西都不记得
I don't remember a thing
你今早好吗  小蜗
How are you this morning, Gary?
我的驾考
My boating exam
要迟到了
I'm late
滑浪学校
希望大家都有好好学
I hope everyone studied
海绵宝宝没来吗
SpongeBob's not here?
多半他弃考了
Maybe he quit
多半我自由了
Maybe I'm free
多半
Maybe
抱歉迟到了  泡芙老师
Sorry I'm late, Mrs. Puff
远不如我心中的遗憾
Not as sorry as I am
同学们  考试开始
Now, class, you may start the exam
答了很多试题之后
好个怪疹子
That's a weird rash
抱歉  泡芙老师
Sorry, Mrs. Puff
我得去上卫生间
I need to go to the restroom
可现在还在
But we're in the middle of a
考试
test
什么
What?
请洗鳍
这玩意谁画的
Who drew this?
我才不长那样子
I don't look like that
同学们停笔
Pencils down, class
第二天早上
怎么回事
What happened?
这什么地方
Where am I?
图书馆
The library
图书馆吗
The library?
我应该是逾期了
I think I'm overdue
得先走了
to leave
裤头村图书馆
最好穿好衣服去上班
I better get dressed and get to work
启动应急裤子
Activate emergency pants
小蜗
Hey, Gary
能载我一程去上班吗
Can you give me a lift to work?
很多小时后
蟹堡王
今天太疯狂了
What a crazy day
能回来做蟹黄堡真好
It's good to get back to flipping patties
海绵宝宝  能帮我顶下班吗
Hey, SpongeBob, can you cover for me?
我得休息一下  来恢复理智
It's time for my sanity break
一次打两份工吗
Two jobs at once?
美梦成真了
A dream come true
随你的便
Knock yourself out
砸 晕 你 自 己
不对  真的
No, really
砸下去
Do it
我想要来点一些吃的
I'd like to order some food
我肚子出现紧急情况了
It's a belly emergency
好啊  派大星
Of course, Patrick
好厉害的魔术
Nice magic trick
再来一遍
Do it again
抱歉  乐谱忘带走了
Sorry, I forgot my sheet music
那个三心二意的白痴哪去了
Where is that scatterbrained sap?
干嘛
Hello
我就在这呢
I'm right here
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
那个小白痴往我点餐本上乱涂乱画
That little twerp doodled all over my order pad
难道是那个铅笔人回来了
Is that DoodleBob thing back?
不对  更严重了
No, it's even worse
免费蟹黄堡
Free Krabby Patty
有点潦草了
A little sketchy
这到底是怎么一回事
What in the name of outboard motors is going on here?
我珍贵的钱
Me precious money
你把我的小宝贝们怎么了
What did you do to me little darlings?
我的壳
Me carapace
露齿牙膏
公交站
放倒我了
I am upended
那只可怕的生物是什么鬼
What was that horrible creature?
我以前见过
I've seen this before
当时我还在海军服役
in me old navy days
海军生涯吗
Old navy days?
你上哪去了
Where have you been?
他很明显跟我们其他人一样被袭击了
He was obviously attacked, like the rest of us
罪魁祸首正是  邪恶的铅笔狼人
by a vicious WereDoodle
泰迪犬人吗
A bear poodle?
不对
No
是铅笔狼人
A WereDoodle
只有一样东西能阻止铅笔狼人
There be only one thing that can stop a WereDoodle
若遇见铅笔狼人请使用
银色橡皮擦
A silver eraser
谁想加入我的武装队
Who wants to join me posse
永远擦掉这只铅笔狼人
and erase this WereDoodle for good?
一起逮着那个二维讨厌鬼
Let's get that two-dimensional twerp
算我一个  蟹老板
Count me in, Mr. Krabs
我好几周没加入武装队了
I haven't been in a posse in weeks
很高兴你能入队  小子
Glad to have you aboard, boy-o
但也得先穿好衣服
But put some clothes on
这就穿  蟹老板
Will do, Mr. Krabs
启动备用应急裤子
Activating backup emergency pants
石墨
Graphite
就在附近
It's close
铅笔
Pencils
来买现削的铅笔
Get your freshly sharpened pencils
不要
No
要画漫画吗  先生
Care for a caricature, sir?
只要说声不用就好了嘛
All you had to say was no thank you
吊挂到我了
I am suspended
铅笔狼人
WereDoodle
我这边有银色橡皮擦
I've got a silver eraser here
而且我还敢使出来
and I'm not afraid to use it
铅笔人
DoodleBob?
它应该是想告诉我们什么
I think it's trying to tell us something
他说铅笔狼人很害怕  还被误解了
He said the WereDoodle is frightened
and misunderstood
你哪位
Who are you?
我是铅笔人的老婆
I'm DoodleBob's wife
告诉他们吧  老公
Tell them, dear
他很抱歉铅笔狼人造成了这么多麻烦
He's sorry WereDoodle caused so much trouble
你说对吧  老公
Isn't that right, dear?
他会解除诅咒
He'll remove the curse
把人家变回正常人
and turn it back into a normal person
不是说好要把他变回正常人吗
Didn't she say a normal person?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你就是那个铅笔狼人吗
You were the WereDoodle?
是吗
I was?
太丢脸了
How embarrassing
铅笔狼人的威胁解除了
The menace of the WereDoodle is over
为铅笔人欢呼
Huzzah for DoodleBob
万岁
Huzzah
多谢你帮忙  铅笔人
Thanks for the help, DoodleBob
被纸划到了
Paper cut
快来铅笔天堂
Come on down to Pencil Paradise
满足你所有铅笔购买需求
for all your pencil needs
猩猩皮套节
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
日历
派大星
Hey, Patrick
今天是
It's
猩猩皮套节
Gorilla Suit Day
有帽子没
Got the hat?
有皮套没  宝贝
Got the suit, baby?
感谢
Thank you
帮我拉拉链
Zip me up?
有根银色的小薯条
A little silver french fry
留着等会儿当点心
A snack for later
我皮套怎么样
How's my costume?
差点就把我给骗到了
You almost fooled me there
来骗大家吧
Let's fool everybody
回来  大猩猩
Come back, gorilla
不好了
Oh no
我的  大猩猩
My "gorilla"
逃出动物园了
has escaped from the zoo
快回来  大猩猩
Come back here, "gorilla"
大猩猩吗
Gorilla?
大猩猩
Gorilla
有发狂的大猩猩
Mad gorilla
不要靠近它嘴巴
Don't get near his mouth
这头大猩猩可饿了
He's a hungry gorilla
便宜货超市
我们把大家都骗到了
We fooled everyone
还真是
We sure did
看来该玩的都玩完了
Well, I guess the fun is over
反正我现在也该去上班了
It's time for me to go to work anyway
帮我解开拉链
Unzip me?
拉链被某个白痴给弄坏了
Some idiot broke the zipper
得把它给锯开
We'll have to saw it off
我没那时间
No time
只能装成大猩猩过去上班了
I'll just go to work as a gorilla
再见
See ya
蟹堡王
早安  章鱼哥
Good morning, Squidward
并不安
No, it isn't
戴着头套不方便看东西啊
Sure is hard to see with this mask on
反正不管穿不穿皮套
But suit or no suit
现在都得来做蟹黄堡
it's time to make the patties
铲铲
Spatty?
Spatty
找到你了
There you are
来看看
Let's see
我需要肉饼
I'll need patties
蔬菜
veggies
面包
buns
一点点这个  一点点那个
Little bit of this, little bit of that
然后
And
瞧好了
voilà
看着挺对劲的
That looks right
是不是
Was it
上菜了
Order up
海绵宝宝  你干嘛
SpongeBob, why are you
是头大猩猩
a gorilla?
是头大腥
A "goriller"?
我才不是大腥  我是大餐厅的厨子
I'm not a "goriller," I'm a griller
是我海绵宝宝啊
It's me, SpongeBob
只是脱不掉这身猩猩皮套而已
I just can't get this gorilla suit off
看
See?
果不其然
Typical
野生动物禁止入内  假的也不行
No wild animals allowed, even fake ones
给我回家
Now go home
脱掉这身猴子皮套才可以回来
and don't come back until you take that monkey suit off
蟹老板  其实大猩猩不算猴子
Actually, Mr. K, gorillas aren't monkeys
它们属于
they're classified as--
滚出去
Get out
一时半会脱不掉
Well, until I get the suit off
不如来好好玩一把
I might as well enjoy it
公交
我们正在现场直播报道
We are live on the scene
直播
发狂大猩猩
于裤头村袭击婴儿
一只撒野的大猩猩正在袭击一名婴儿
where a rampaging wild gorilla is attacking a baby
什么
What?
请问一下  先生
Excuse me, sir
你是饲养员吗
Are you a zookeeper?
没错  我就是
Why, yes, I am
我的大猩猩逃出动物园了
My gorilla has escaped from the zoo
饲养员确认
大猩猩是邪恶的
情况就是这样
There you have it, folks
每位家长最可怕的噩梦
Every parent's worst nightmare
接下来的任务交给动物管理局
Animal control will take over from here
派大星
Patrick
想办法救我啊
Do something
放心  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
我不会破坏恶作剧的
I won't ruin the prank
派大星
Patrick
裤头村动物园
都说过我真的不是大猩猩了
I told you, I'm not a real gorilla
今天可是猩猩皮套节
Today is Gorilla Suit Day
大猩猩都用这套话术
That's what all the gorillas say
回里面待着去
Now get back in there
别给我犟了  你个顽固的灵长类
Settle down, you pigheaded primate
嗨  猩猩们
Hi, gorillas
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob
宝贝快看  有大猩猩
Look, hon, gorillas
完全没准备  不过我尽力
I didn't prepare anything but I'll do my best
还有免费花生啊
Free peanuts?
我不脱这身皮套了
I'm never taking this suit off
我们到了  菲菲
Here we are, Fifi
该吃好吃的了
Time for yum-yums
你还能炫耀新买的这身金黄毛衣哦
And you can show off your new gold sweater
菜单
菲菲
Fifi
冒犯到我虫子了
My worm is offended
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我都叫你脱掉这身猩猩皮套了
I said take that gorilla suit off
海绵宝宝  你个畜生
SpongeBob, you animal
那些蟹黄堡的钱得从你工资扣
Those patties are coming out of your pay
你可炸不了我  我都没被暴打
You can't fry me, I'm not even battered
裹 面 糊
海绵宝宝今天的表现比平常还诡异
SpongeBob sure is acting weirder than usual today
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
放我下来
Put me down
你可骗不到人  光凭你这
You're not fooling anyone with your
我恨猩猩皮套节
I hate Gorilla Suit Day
长官  发现大猩猩
Chief, we found the gorilla
请求进一步指示
Requesting orders
求救
Mayday
我们正在泡芙老师的灯塔现场报道
We are live at Mrs. Puff's lighthouse
又一头出逃的大猩猩正在此大搞破坏
where another escaped gorilla is wreaking havoc
我身边的还是这位大猩猩饲养员
With me again is the gorilla's zookeeper
兄弟
Hey, buddy
我们这个恶作剧好像做得有点过头了
I think we might be taking this prank a little too far
我本来还要吃这个的
I was gonna eat this
不过貌似可以拿它
but perhaps it could be used
当拉链来用
as some sort of zipping implement
那就来帮你把这身皮套脱下来吧
So let's try and get that suit off ya
来脱了
Here we go
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你什么时候开始穿的平角裤
Since when do you wear boxers?
十二点钟方向掉了只大猩猩
Falling gorilla at 12 o'clock
脆脆的
Crunchy
你好啊
Hello
要来一起吃吗
Care to join us?
我今天虱子吃得够多了
I think I've eaten enough lice today
再见
Bye
这身皮套脱不掉  还怎么回去上班
How can I go back to work if I can't get this suit off?
有办法了
I've got an idea
裤头村皮套供应
黄色海绵人
小号
一件黄色海绵人皮套
One Yellow Sponge Person costume
正好
Perfect
好了
There
焕然一新
Good as new
海绵宝宝  你回来了
SpongeBob, you're back
对
Yup
而且还正是时候呢
And just in time, too
因为你也知道  明天可是
Because as you know, tomorrow is
袋鼠皮套节
Kangaroo Suit Day
我都迫不及待了  不想等到明早
I can't wait until morning
来抢先跳一跳吧
Let's get a jump on it
这辈子都再也不想看到一头大猩猩了
If I never see another gorilla, it'll be too soon
不会吧
Oh no
还有一头
Another one